Never capture what you can't control.
Blackfish is a documentary film directed by Gabriela Cowperthwaite.
Notorious killer whale Tilikum is responsible for the deaths of three
individuals, including a top killer whale trainer.
Blackfish shows the sometimes devastating consequences of keeping
such intelligent and sentient creatures in captivity.
Self, played by Dean Gomersall.
Self, played by Samantha Berg.
Self, played by John Jett.
Self, played by John Hargrove.
Self, played by Carol Ray.
Self, played by Jeffrey Ventre.
Blackfish is a 2013 American documentary film
directed by Gabriela Cowperthwaite.
It concerns Tilikum, an orca held by SeaWorld and
the controversy over captive orcas.
The film premiered at the 2013 Sundance Film Festival on January 19, 2013, and was
picked up by Magnolia Pictures and CNN Films for wider release.
It was nominated for the BAFTA Award for Best Documentary.
The film explores themes of whale, trauma,
controversy, psychological thriller, nature.
The tone is mind_bending.